# **André Rodrigues Ferraz**

Software Engineer

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil

+55 31 997102160

oandreferraz@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/andre-rodrigues-ferraz

github.com/andreferrazz

andreferraz.com

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

As a Backend Engineer at a leading tech company, my primary focus is improving the community association experience by facilitating communication between residents, HOA board members and the manager.

With a solid foundation in Java and Spring Boot (which I've been honing since 2019), I'm well-prepared to tackle any project. In addition to my professional experience with a product that caters to a vast user base of over a million people, I've created side project applications that meet real-world expectations. My coding journey began in 2018, as a self-taught software engineer. Since the beginning Java and Spring were my primary focus, but to get to where I am now I needed to learn many other technologies. Some of them are Angular, Svelte, Express, Elixir and AWS.

#### **SKILLS**

- Backend Development
- Java and Spring
- Angular

- AWS (EC2, SQS, S3...)
- Elixir and Phoenix (Learning)
- SvelteKit (Learning)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Fullstack Developer - Group Software**

February 2022 - present

As a Fullstack Developer at Group Software, my focus is building and maintaining web applications that improve the experience of hundreds of thousands of residents in community associations in countries such as the US, Mexico and Brazil. My daily work routine is guided by Scrum and the main technologies used are Java, Spring, AngularJS and AWS.

#### Fullstack Developer - Grupo SFA

January 2021 - January 2022

At Group SFA I helped build and maintain a variety of web applications including accounting automation, shopping centers management, productivity tools and more. To do that we rely on technologies such as Java, Spring, Angular and Flutter. The work routine was guided by the agile Scrum methodology.

### **Software Developer Intern - Grupo Ciatos**

June 2020 - January 2021

To help coworking users rent workstations and consume some services, I designed and built a full stack application using Java/Spring, React and Ionic.

#### **EDUCATION**

Technical Diploma in Systems Development
UFMG Technical College - Belo Horizonte/MG - Brazil